websitebuilderexpert.com 2019-05-02

# Privacy Policy

**You have certain rights in relation to your data, including the right to object to processing based on legitimate interests, profiling (including the use of custom and lookalike/similar audiences), and direct marketing. At any time, you can exercise your rights by emailing us at dataprotection@mvfglobal.com. For further details about our processing and your rights, please see below.**

## Contents

  * About our site
  * About us
  * What data we collect, and how we use it
  * Cookies
  * Transferring your data
  * Storing your data
  * Legal grounds
  * Your rights
  * Contacting us
  * Changes to this notice
  * Cookies table

## About our site

WebsiteBuilderExpert.com (“ **our site** ”) is an online resource for technology and related news and information.

## About us

Website Builder Expert is a brand of Marketing VF Limited (“ **MVF** ”, “ **we** ”, “ **us** ”, “ **our** ”).

MVF is a company registered in England and Wales (company number: 06951544), whose registered office address is at Imperial Works, Perren Street, London NW5 3ED, United Kingdom.

For the purposes of the General Data Protection Regulation (the “ **GDPR** ”), Marketing VF Limited is the controller in relation to your data. We are registered as a controller with the UK Information Commissioner’s Office (“ **ICO** ”) under registration number Z1995728. You can confirm our registration here: [www.ico.org.uk](https://ico.org.uk/)

## What data we collect and how we use it

### Subscribing to our newsletters, guides and deals:

You can subscribe to our newsletters, guides and deals (“ **Emails** ”) by completing and submitting the webform on our site. The webform will ask you for your email address.

If you subscribe, we will send you an email with a link, asking you to confirm your email address and subscription. If you click on the link, we will send our Emails to you periodically. At any time, you can unsubscribe from our Emails.

### Posting comments:

If you wish to post any comments on our site, you will need to provide your name and email address. If we approve your comment, it will be posted on our site with the name you provide. Your email address will not be published, and is requested only to help us prevent spam.

### Contacting us:

We will receive information about you (e.g. your name and email address) if you contact us through our site, or by email or post.

If you contact us, we will use your information to handle your enquiry and correspond with you.

### Creating custom and lookalike/similar audiences:

We may work with Facebook and other platforms (“ **Platforms** ”) to reach out to you with adverts. We also like to use Platforms to reach out to other people who might like to use our sites and service.

We do this in two ways. In both cases, your data, along with other data, is used to create a custom audience and/or a lookalike/similar audience. Whenever an audience is shared with a Platform, the data is first hashed and pseudonymised, meaning that any data within the audience that could identify a person is replaced with an artificial identifier. So, the process is secure. Also, we don’t share more data than we need to for the purpose of creating the audience.

  * **Custom audience** – A custom audience is a list of existing users of our sites and service (“ **Existing Users** ”). From time to time, we share this with Platforms. As explained above, the data is first hashed and pseudonymised. The Platform uses this audience to show our Existing Users our adverts.
  * **Lookalike/similar audience** – A lookalike/similar audience is an audience created by the Platform. From time to time, we share with Platforms a list of Existing Users. The Platform uses this list to find and create lookalikes – i.e. other Platform users who have similar characteristics to the Existing Users – to which it shows our adverts. Again, as explained above, the data is first hashed and pseudonymised.

As we explain below, at any time, you may object to such activity by emailing us at dataprotection@mvfglobal.com.

### Understanding and improving website conversions

We work with a click tracker to capture and store Internet Protocol (IP) addresses. Every computer or device has an IP address - a unique number - which enables it to communicate with other computers and devices over the Internet. We store IP addresses in order to understand which countries our website conversions come from. We then use this data to optimise our campaigns, in order to improve our conversion rates.

### Receiving data from our partners:

From time to time, our partners (i.e. website builders) may share data with us. In most cases, they do this anonymously (i.e. they don’t provide us with any personal data). If you visit Shopify’s site from our site, and subsequently open a Shopify account, they will tell us the name of your online store. We don’t use this information for any purpose, except to record the number of visitors from our site who have opened a Shopify account.

### Working with suppliers:

We work with a number of suppliers, who process data on our behalf. These include cloud storage providers, email service providers, and cloud telephony providers. We have appropriate contracts in place with such suppliers to ensure the protection and confidentiality of data.

## Cookies

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the owners of the site. At the bottom of this policy, we have included a table, setting out what cookies we use, and the purposes for which we use them.

Most web browsers allow some control of most cookies through the browser settings. To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to manage and delete them, visit [www.aboutcookies.org](https://www.aboutcookies.org/) or [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)

To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>

## Transferring your data

We may transfer your data to countries outside the European Economic Area (the “ **EEA** ”).

Some of those countries have a European Commission adequacy decision, which means they are considered to offer an adequate level of data protection.

Other countries do not have the same level of legal protection as countries in the EEA, or with an adequacy decision. If we do transfer your data in this way, we will take steps to ensure that it is protected to the same levels that apply in the EEA. This may include, for example, ensuring that the organisation receiving the data is registered with the EU-US Privacy Shield (in the case of transfers to the USA), or that we use the EU’s model contract clauses.

## Storing your data

We have a data retention policy, which clearly sets out how long we keep data for, and for what reasons.

We will keep your data only for as long as is necessary to fulfil the purpose/s for which it was collected in the first place, i.e. as set out in this notice.

## Legal grounds

This notice sets out (above) how we use your data. Under the GDPR, controllers must have a valid lawful basis for each processing activity that they undertake. This section sets out our lawful basis for each activity.

Activity | Lawful basis under the GDPR  
---|---  
Sending our Emails to you | Consent  
Posting comments on our site | Legitimate interests  
Handling enquiries received from you | Legitimate interests  
Creating custom and lookalike/similar audiences | Legitimate interests  
Receiving data from our partners | Legitimate interests  
  
## Your rights

Under the GDPR, you have a number of rights, which are explained below.

**Right of access** – You have the right at any time to ask us for a copy of the personal information that we hold about you, and to check that we are lawfully processing it.

**Right of rectification** – If personal information that we hold about you is not accurate or is out of date and requires amendment or correction you have a right to have the data rectified or completed.

**Right of erasure** – In certain circumstances, you have the right to request that personal information we hold about you is erased (e.g. if the information is no longer necessary for the purposes for which it was collected or processed).

**Right to object to or restrict processing** – In certain circumstances, you have the right to object to our processing of your personal information. For example, if we are processing your information on the basis of our legitimate interests, and there are no compelling legitimate grounds for our processing which override your rights and interests.

**Right of data portability** – In certain instances, you have a right to receive any personal information that we hold about you in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format.

**Right to withdraw consent** – In the limited circumstances where you may have provided your consent to the collection, processing and transfer of your personal information for a specific purpose, you have the right to withdraw your consent for that specific processing at any time.

### Exercising your rights

If you wish to exercise any of your rights under the GDPR, please email us at dataprotection@mvfglobal.com. Alternatively, you can write to us at the address set out above, or inform us if you speak with us on the phone.

Our lead supervisory authority for the processing set out in this notice is the UK ICO. If you are unhappy with how we have processed your data, you have the right to make a complaint to the ICO.

If you are based outside of the UK, or you have a complaint concerning our activities outside of the UK, you may prefer to lodge a complaint with a different Supervisory Authority. A list of relevant authorities can be accessed here: <http://ec.europa.eu/newsroom/article29/item-detail.cfm?item_id=612080>.

## Contacting us

If you have any questions regarding this notice, or any questions relating to data protection or privacy, you can contact us at dataprotection@mvfglobal.com.

Alternatively, you can write to us at the address set out above.

## Changes to this notice

From time to time, we may update this notice.

## Cookies table

When you visit any of our partners’ sites from our site (e.g. by clicking on a link), the partner will place a cookie on your computer/device. They do this so that both they and we know the number of visitors from our site who upgrade to a premium account (if they choose to do so), as explained [here](https://www.websitebuilderexpert.com/disclosure/).

**Cookie** | **Name** | **Purpose**  
---|---|---  
**Universal Analytics (Google)** | _ga  
_gali  
_gat_UA-1036645-1  
_gid | 

These cookies collect information about how visitors use our website. We use the information to compile reports and to make improvements. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including where visitors have come to the website from and the pages they visited.

To opt-out: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>  
  
**Taboola Retargeting** |  | 

These cookies are used to tailor Taboola adverts to a user’s previous viewing habits. For instance, if you have previously visited our page, you may then see other adverts related to that product or service. Taboola is an ad network that shows sponsored content, usually as links below the article on major news sites.  
  
Adwords Retargeting (Google) |  | 

These cookies are used to adjust the targeting of our paid search and display advertising to show ads to users who have previously been to our sites and/or engaged with our page such as completing a form. They contain no personal information.  
  
DoubleClick Retargeting |  | 

These cookies are used to adjust the targeting of our display advertising to show ads to users who have previously been to our sites and/or engaged with our page such as completing a form. They contain no personal information.  
  
Taboola Conversion Tracking |  | 

These cookies measure ad conversions and optimise spend for advertising campaigns served on Taboola.  
  
Adwords Conversion Tracking |  | 

These cookies measure when a user has completed an action on site such as completing a form. They contain no personal information.  
  
DoubleClick Conversion Tracking |  | 

These cookies measure when a user has completed an action on site such as completing a form. They contain no personal information.  
  
Facebook Pixel |  | 

These cookies measure ad conversions, optimise and build audiences for advertising campaigns served on Facebook.

To opt-out: <https://www.facebook.com/policies/cookies/>  
  
VWO | _vwo | 

These cookies are used to help us optimise our sites by running tests and measuring user conversions. It is also used to track user information when visiting the site (e.g. browser and device information).  
  
HotJar |  | 

Hotjar uses cookies and other technologies to collect data on our users’ behaviour (e.g. how much time they spend on which pages, which links they choose to click etc) and their devices (in particular device’s IP address, captured and stored only in anonymised form, preferred language settings etc). This enables us to better understand our users’ needs and to optimise this service and experience.

Hotjar stores this information in a pseudonymised user profile. Neither Hotjar nor we will ever use this information to identify individual users or to match it with further data on an individual user.

To opt out: <https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out>  
  
OptinMonster |  | 

This cookie uses proprietary customer acquisition & lead generation software to help us optimise our sites by running tests and measuring user conversions.  
  
**Last reviewed: 24 May 2018**
